{
  "version": 2.0,
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "For a simple pendulum the time period of one oscillation is given by",
      "answers": {
        "a": "2 π √ g/l",
        "b": "2 π √ 2l/g",
        "c": "2 √ l/ 2g",
        "d": "2 π √ l/g"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "For a simple pendulum, time period for a beat, is",
      "answers": {
        "a": " π √ l/g",
        "b": "π √ 2l/g",
        "c": "π √ g/2l",
        "d": "π √ l/2g"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "In order to double the period of a simple pendulum, the length of the string should be",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Halved",
        "b": "Doubled",
        "c": "Quadrupled",
        "d": "None of the Above"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "For a linear time in variant system, an optimal controller can be designed if",
      "answers": {
        "a": "The system is controllable and observable",
        "b": "The system is uncontrollable but stable",
        "c": "The system is unstable but observable",
        "d": "The system is stable but unobservable"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "If a spring of mass 20kg has spring constant of 5N/m, then the time period is given by,",
      "answers": {
        "a": "4",
        "b": "2",
        "c": "2π",
        "d": "4π"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
	{
      "question": "A slow running pendulum clock can be speeded up by,",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Increasing the length of the rod",
        "b": "Increasing the weight of the bob",
        "c": "Reducing the length of the rod",
        "d": "Reducing the weight of the bob"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },	
	
	{
      "question": "If a clock, based on oscillating pendulum is taken to the Moon, it will",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Become slow",
        "b": "Become fast",
        "c": "Gives same time as on Earth",
        "d": "Stop working"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
	
	{
      "question": "Which of the following variables has zero value at the extreme position in SHM?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Acceleration",
        "b": "Speed",
        "c": "Displacement",
        "d": "Angular Frequency"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
	
	
	{
      "question": "The period of simple pendulum inside the satellite orbiting earth is",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Zero",
        "b": "2T",
        "c": "T",
        "d": "Infinite"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
	
	{
      "question": "A simple pendulum,having time period T,mass of the bob is made one fourth , then time period will be",
      "answers": {
        "a": "2T",
        "b": "4T",
        "c": "0.707T",
        "d": "T"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    }
	
  ]
}
